there. How does that how do you use that
on the field to your advantage?
>> Uh, I mean, of course, like when if I'm
in the B line of the quarterback
throwing the ball, I feel like that
that's a that's a great opportunity to
for me to showcase that uh vert by
trying to knocking it by swatting it
down. Um, in my 40 just uh when when
guys see me, I think running backs like
take it for count like, oh, he's he's
big, he not he not fast. So, I think
that's a attribute that I I love
showcasing um you know to let uh smaller
guys know that I'm not slow.
>> Damonte, you're joining a defensive line
room with some serious attitude with
Vita and Aan Robinson who they signed in
free agency. How excited are you to now
be in the mix?
>> Uh I'm I'm I'm very excited. um ready to
um you know be a part of that room,
learn from that room and you know cuz
that's a lot of veteran guys just just
want to come be a part and figure out
how to help that help those guys uh help
help them win.
>> You have a high school basketball
background, correct?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Can you talk a little bit about how you
feel like that helps you when you're on
the the football field?
>> Uh just, you know, quickness. I think my
first step that helps first step uh just
things of that nature, but um most
importantly footwork
uh with basketball.
>> Can you talk
>> Can you talk about the call uh that when
you received the call, you're getting
drafted by the Bucks. Where are you?
What was that emotion like? What did
that mean to you?
>> Um well, I remember what coach Bulls
told me when I came down for my 30
visit. It just played in my head so many
times uh that we we was we would talk
again and um that just that just was one
of the things that kept playing in my
head when I seen my phone buzzing. I was
like, "Oh my god, no way."
>> Uh the Bucks defense typically requires
defensive linemen to be very versatile
playing shade three, four eye, five. Is
there a specific position that you get
really excited to get into in terms of a
specific gap and be able to attack from?
Me personally, I love it all because
it's just it's all the same thing if you
think about it. You just it's just where
you aligning at. I like if if you a two
eye, you can play the three. If you
three eye, you can play the four. Like
it's it's all the same thing. It's just
um it's just bumping you out out farther
away. That's all I see it as. So, I
think I'm very uh talented and
versatile. I think I can play all of
them and I'm I'm excited, you know, when
when I So, me personally, when I get in
the nose position, I that's where I feel
like I'm dominant because my quick first
step on the centers and guards and stuff
like that. So, yeah.
>> What would you say your biggest strength
is and and what you're bringing what you
can bring to this team down here in
Tampa Bay?
>> Um, my biggest strength is uh like I
said, being violent uh and just, you
know, stopping the run. And what do you
think you can bring to the the defense?
>> Uh, [clears throat] I think I can bring
uh tenacity, uh that energy, uh that
that that that swagger um to that
defense.
>> When you're defending the run, you got a
double team coming up against you. What
is your I guess go-to way to try and
anchor down and prevent them from
getting vertical displacement on you?
>> What we say again?
>> What's your go-to in terms of trying to
stop double teams from moving you off
your gap?
Uh, I like to throw my hip into the to
the guard or or the tackle essentially.
Uh, so I just like to I don't really
drop the knee. I always try to like
brace my brace my uh inside leg and
throw my hip into the the pressure.
>> Appreciate you. Do
>> you had a If you could say anything to
the Bucks fans who are watching right
now, what what kind of player what kind
of person what are they getting out of
you?
>> Uh, for all the Bucks fan, you you're
getting a guy that's committed. a guy
that knows what he wants and know knows
what to bring every single day. A guy
that knows how to work and and a guy
that uh gonna give y'all his all.
>> All right.
Congratulations.
>> Thank y'all. Appreciate y'all.
>> See you out here.
SC game. Um, what I've heard, you
suffered that knee injury pretty early
in the game and just kept working. Can
you talk a little bit about what what
went into your decision that, you know,
I'm going to continue to play through
this?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I think whenever you
get the chance and the the medical team,
you know, gives you the the option to go
back out there, it's, you know, it's not
really an option. You you love to go
play with those guys. Um, yeah, so no
regrets. You know, I love I love playing
the game and I don't take any moment out
there for granted and, you know, having
the opportunity to get back out there
with my guys was was all I wanted.
Billy, Notre Dame is one of the most
prestigious programs in all of college
football. With that being said, how much
did it mean for you to be a team
captain?
>> Yeah, it was awesome. Uh I love those
guys in that locker room, you know, like
brothers and you know, to be uh
to be uh you know, thought of as as a
leader in in that uh not only my room
but in the whole locker room is uh it's
a huge honor.
really had you talked to the Bucks much
in the in the draft process. Is this
something you thought might be happening
or
>> Yeah, you know, talked with them, met
with them probably two two or three
times, but uh yeah, had a had a decent
feeling, but uh you know, I think you
never really know until until your
phone, uh starts ringing, but uh yeah,
super fired up for the opportunity. And
what was that moment like when when you
looked down and you saw the 813 and
you're with your family like what what
was that moment like? Talk about it. a
lot of gratitude. You know, kind of
kind of uh you know, it's been it's been
a different little journey here the last
couple months, but trying to stay in the
moment with all of it and uh you know,
put my put my foot forward, you know,
and uh you know, super fired up to be in
in Tampa and and in Florida. You know, I
think it's a good fit.
It's one thing to block the guy straight
across from you, but part of your
scouting report is that you have a a
high level of awareness to be able to
pick up blocks from angles that you know
maybe not um predictable. Can you talk a
little bit about how you're able to find
those loopers, those stuners, the
blitzers, and make sure that the pocket
stays clean?
>> Yeah, I think it's number one playing
with the guys next to you. Um it's five
is one. um everything's got to be done
together at the offensive line
positions. So, I think that's number
one. And then, you know, you got to be
prepared. Um you got to kind of see
things un unraveling as they're uh um
you know, as they're lined up. You can't
be can't be late with everything or with
anything. Um so, I think those two
things, but uh you know, taking care of
the guys next to you is huge. Bill, how
would you kind of describe your play
style, your mentality when you go out on
the football field?
>> Yeah. Um, you love get getting after
guys. Um,
I think I always, you know, try to uh
try to be a good teammate, try to take
care of the guys next to me, but in in
doing so, I like to uh, you know, I like
to play physical. I like uh I like uh
getting after dudes, you know, playing
uh playing the game the way it's
supposed to be played, fast, strong,
powerful.
>> Billy, you blocked for two first round
running backs and Jeremiah and Jadarian.
When it comes to run blocking
specifically, what do you enjoy most
about it? And is it laying guys in the
dirt or
>> I think it's, you know, moving a a man
against his will is is awesome. You
know, there's not many sports where you
can express yourself physically like
that and get after people. And I think,
you know, I never feel more like myself
than when I'm out playing football. And,
you know, run blocking is a huge part of
that for me.
>> Bill, I think they they like you as a
guard, obviously, what you played. If
you were to cross train, would you be
more likely to step outside to tackle or
or inside to center, do you think?
>> I'd be comfortable wherever. You know, I
uh I love playing ball and uh you know,
finding a way to uh get out there and
help the Buccaneers win football games
is that's number one for me.
>> What do you think? What do you think you
can bring to the Buccaneers?
>> I'm bringing edge, you know. Um I uh I
play the game a certain way and uh you
know, I think that's that's that's
number one. But, uh, you know, I'm I
love to win and you know, I'll always
play the game to win. I think that's
that's number one. So, you know, just
getting out there doing everything I can
to uh,
like I said, help this team win ball
games.
>> Billy, this time last year, they they
brought in Benjamin Morrison from Notre
Dame. Do you know him well?
>> Yeah, I do know Beimo. Yeah, we came in
the same class
at uh at Notre Dame and he uh you know,
he's great dude and great football
player.
Bill, you're you're from a small town in
Wisconsin of a population of less than
2,000. Just how much has the journey
from, you know, growing up there to
going to Notre Dame and now being in the
NFL?
>> Yeah. Um
it's awesome. you know, not many people
have have done what I'm I'm doing. And I
think uh you know, it's it's really a
credit to my my family and my community
and you know, I'm just
you know, I'm kind of where the the
light light is shining. But there's a
lot of people that uh that have helped
me get to where where I've gotten and uh
I'm super grateful for them. you know,
my uh my family's awesome. And you know,
growing up in that small community, I
also had a lot of friends and and uh you
know, even cousins, uncles, you know,
who uh you know, show me the right way
to do things and go about things. I
think that's that's probably what I
remember the most with throughout my
journey. Billy, when when you look at
today, it's obviously, you know, it's
it's an amazing day for you, but that
injury kind of maybe robbed you of maybe
a higher draft slot. Does that give you
any any chip on your shoulder to
motivate that, hey, like this is where I
landed, but this is not where I end?
>> Yeah, you know, I'm right where I'm
supposed to be. I uh think everything
happens for a reason. I I think this is
a great fit and, you know, I'm always
highly motivated. Um, that's just that's
who I am. Uh, and I I think
motivation isn't isn't something I uh,
you know, I I uh I I look for all the
time, you know, it's always kind of I'm
grateful to kind of have that that
within me. Um, so
>> Bill, your knee, you full go back to
health on that.
>> Full fully healthy. Yep. Ready for camp.
And Bill, your your last name, you
pronounce Shrath. Is that right?
>> Correct. Outstanding. So,
>> if you had a message for any of the
Bucks fans who are watching this right
now, what kind of player, what kind of
person are they getting with you?
>> Yeah. Physical
physical guy who uh you know, wants to
help the team win. And uh I'll uh you
know, I'll be a I'll be a culture guy. I
spent a lot of time in the, you know,
the locker room and in the old line room
and in the facility and I think uh, you
know, it shows up. I try to bring try to
bring energy to guys and my teammates
and and not take it.
>> All right, Billy. Thank you very much.
>> Congratulations.
>> Thank you guys.